Shirish Ramchandran

Senior Software Engineer

shirish.ramchandran@gmail.com | +91-9158999636 Pune, MH

<u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u>

❖ PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Agile Software Engineer talented at contributing to multi-team development projects. Collaborative designer of exceptionally useful solutions and perfectly customized products. Well-versed with software design and development, bringing 6+ years of work experience in the software industry.

❖ TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Proficient in Java
- Exposure to Python & Angular
- Technical Analysis

- Software Documentation
- Design Reviews
- Product Development

WORK HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer | Niyuj Enterprise Software Solutions - Pune, MH 06/2020 - Present

- Responsibilities: Development and support for a US- based Healthcare product.
- Developed code using **Java** and other programming languages to enhance the product and integrate systems.
- Evaluated project requirements and specifications and developed software applications that surpassed client expectations.
- Wrote, maintained and managed test documentation, manuals for the data migration project.
- Languages/ Framework: Java 8, Spring Boot, Python, Angular.
- Tools: Intellij, Git, Jenkins, Sentry, Sumo logic, Postman.
- Database: PostgreSQL.

Member Of Technical Staff | Shoptimize India Pvt. Ltd. - Pune, MH

03/2017 - 06/2020

- Worked as the **Team Lead** for an e-commerce product.
- Implemented process improvements to smooth the development cycle and increase collaboration.
- Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that met or exceeded performance expectations.
- Provided guidance and direction to less experienced staff in resolution of highly complex technical problems.

- Worked on various e-commerce integrations including Salesforce CRM, WMS.
- Payment gateway integrations such as Razorpay, PayTM, PayPal, etc.
- Languages/ Framework: PHP 7, Magento 2 (CE), JQuery.
- Other software: Varnish, Elasticsearch.
- Hosting: AWS.Database: MySQL.

Software Development Engineer | Arvind Internet, A division of Arvind Limited - Bangalore, KA

07/2015 - 03/2017

- Participated in a complete software development lifecycle, including performance analysis, design, development and testing.
- Developed Order Management System (OMS) for nnnow.com (Omuni).
- Met with project manager and team members to provide detailed project reports and milestone updates.
- Worked on integration with SAP & POS systems.
- Worked on a project for Order Process Automation & Orchestration using Camunda BPM
- Languages/ Framework: Java, Spring Boot.
- Tools: JHipster, Git, Jenkins, Gradle.
- Hosting: AWS.Database: MySQL.

*** OTHER EXPERIENCE**

Student Coordinator, Placement Cell | Department of Computer Science, University of Pune 06/2014 - 05/2015

*** EDUCATION**

Pune University (PUCSD) 2015

Master of Computer Science

GPA: 4.6/6

Fergusson College, Pune 2013

Bachelor of Computer Science

74.78 %

HOBBIES

Landscape and Cityscape photography enthusiast. Currently undergoing training with Ranvaata Photography Institute, Thane.